<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://doctorpsi.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://doctorpsi.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-01T04:22:02+05:30</updated><id>https://doctorpsi.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Doctor Psi</title><subtitle>A simpleton who loves to share.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Enchanted by Strings | Part 1</title><link href="https://doctorpsi.github.io/2020/05/25/enchanted-by-strings-part-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Enchanted by Strings | Part 1" /><published>2020-05-25T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-25T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://doctorpsi.github.io/2020/05/25/enchanted-by-strings-part-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorpsi.github.io/2020/05/25/enchanted-by-strings-part-1.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt;: This series consists of my personal notes on a beautiful chapter on &lt;em&gt;polymers&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;membranes&lt;/em&gt; that I found amusing. The contents of this blog are directly taken from here. Please refer to the original text of &lt;em&gt;Equilibrium Statistical Physics&lt;/em&gt; by Plischke &amp;amp; Bergersen for more details. If you are afraid of math and scary looking equations, then this post and the others are not for you. The material covered is pretty elementary though, suitable for an ambitious upper undergraduate or a graduate (presumably in Physics).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In this episode, we discuss the basic aspects of the statistical mechanics of flexible linear polymers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As promised in our &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/05/23/enchanted-by-strings-part-0.html&quot;&gt;last episode&lt;/a&gt;, we will now discuss linear polymers, which is the simplest architecture or topology we can think of. In what follows, we will treat polymers to be simply long flexble chains. Imagine a really long string or a spaghetti strand. We will ignore all the microscopic details as mentioned before. Plischke &amp;amp; Bergersen give a quick run through the basic chemistry of the flexibility mechanism right at the beginning. We will, however, skip this portion and jump straight to the interesting part. The reader is strongly encouraged to refer to the original text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to talk about flexibility, it is fairly intuitive that as you go along the chain there will be a rapid loss of “memory”. What we mean by memory will be clear in a second. There is a peculiar length scale &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;l&lt;/script&gt; over which the bond orientations become uncorrelated, known as the &lt;em&gt;persistence length&lt;/em&gt;. It is an important feature which gives flexible polymers their universal structural properties. This length depends on microscopic details and is different for various kinds of polymers. Any polymer having its persistence length much smaller than the contour length, &lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;l \ll Na&lt;/script&gt; ( &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;a&lt;/script&gt; being the bond length) should have physical properties depending &lt;em&gt;universally&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;Na/l&lt;/script&gt;. This is true because one can always think in terms of beads or monomers of size &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;l&lt;/script&gt; instead of actual atoms &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Chain segments smaller than the persistence length are practically straight (correlations “persist”). On the other hand, if we consider lengths greater than &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;l&lt;/script&gt;, we see that the correlations now vanish entirely allowing the chain to freely flex or bend. The polymer chain can then be treated as a long flexible mass of &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;Na/l&lt;/script&gt; links, with all its global properties depending only on this particular number (“universality”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the highly disordered bond orientations make the polymer configuration close in many ways to a &lt;em&gt;biased random walk&lt;/em&gt;. For flexible polymers, we will show that the statistical mechanics of these systems is nothing but a maximization of the entropy of a random walk to a first approximation. However, this deep connection or rather analogy does not make the polymer problem any simpler. In fact, it is far more challenging than the familiar random walk problem as the polymer chain can never cross itself. The atoms on the chain have hard core repulsion which prevent them from occupying the same region in space. So we have what is called a &lt;em&gt;self-avoiding walk&lt;/em&gt;, which is not so easy to deal with. The chain expands (or swells) in a nontrivial manner at least for dimensions &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;% &lt;![CDATA[
d &lt; 4 %]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;, which is the &lt;em&gt;upper critical dimension&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; for our problem at hand. We will talk more about this concept later since it plays an important role in the study of critical phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the appearance of an upper critical dimension hints at something really deep: the polymer problem is in a sense a critical phenomenon problem. We shall see soon that this is certainly true. It is this duality which allows us to cleverly map the former onto the latter, and hence take advantage of the huge wealth of information that is known about critical phenomena (along with its rich machinery &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). It should be noted that this hardcore (or &lt;em&gt;excluded volume&lt;/em&gt;) interaction, although short ranged in &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;d&lt;/script&gt;-dimensional space is &lt;em&gt;long ranged&lt;/em&gt; if we consider the distance along the chain. Monomers far apart along the chain can interact strongly if the chain folds back unto itself. This feature makes our polymer problem a highly nontrivial one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next section, we begin our main discussion of the statistical mechanics of polymers by taking the simplest model, &lt;em&gt;viz.&lt;/em&gt; the “freely jointed chain”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-freely-jointed-chain&quot;&gt;The freely jointed chain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;COMING SOON&lt;/em&gt; . . . :trident:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This is the gist of &lt;em&gt;coarse-graining&lt;/em&gt; we talked about earlier. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;See any text on phase transitions and critical phenomena for this. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The rich mathematical language of field theory and the renormalization group. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">TL;DR: This series consists of my personal notes on a beautiful chapter on polymers and membranes that I found amusing. The contents of this blog are directly taken from here. Please refer to the original text of Equilibrium Statistical Physics by Plischke &amp;amp; Bergersen for more details. If you are afraid of math and scary looking equations, then this post and the others are not for you. The material covered is pretty elementary though, suitable for an ambitious upper undergraduate or a graduate (presumably in Physics). In this episode, we discuss the basic aspects of the statistical mechanics of flexible linear polymers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Enchanted by Strings | Part 0</title><link href="https://doctorpsi.github.io/2020/05/23/enchanted-by-strings-part-0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Enchanted by Strings | Part 0" /><published>2020-05-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://doctorpsi.github.io/2020/05/23/enchanted-by-strings-part-0</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorpsi.github.io/2020/05/23/enchanted-by-strings-part-0.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt;: This series is an ode to a beautiful chapter on polymers and membranes in the classic text of &lt;em&gt;Equilibrium Statistical Physics&lt;/em&gt; by Plischke &amp;amp; Bergersen. All the contents to be shared are copied. The author of this blog claims no originality whatsoever. Our aim is solely to guide you through the text and open your eyes to a whole new world, which we believe is often overlooked and misunderstood. If you are afraid of math and scary looking equations, then this post and the upcoming ones are not for you. The contents of the text is pretty elementary though, suitable for an ambitious upper undergraduate or a graduate (in Physics presumably).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;polymers-ahoy&quot;&gt;Polymers &lt;em&gt;Ahoy!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this series we will study the statistical mechanics of linear polymers as well as fluid and tethered membranes. Other exotic polymer shapes or architectures, like &lt;em&gt;ring polymers&lt;/em&gt;, will not be discussed here. These are beautiful in their own right and deserve a separate series, which we also plan to do soon. Polymers have captured the attention of physicists for decades now, and the emerging field of Polymer Phyics is still of great interest. Polymers are all around us and are essential for sustaining life. Plastics, DNA, you name it! In spite of this, they have continuously failed to live up to their full glory. Simply because these humble entities hardly capture the wild imagination of the general public as strongly as the mysterious Black Holes or the magical “strings” of String Theory do. It is quite sad a state of affairs. We just wish if it were otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this brief preamble, we will now embark on an adventurous journey to the magical world of “giant molecules”. We will try to make the material as interesting as possible, adding along extra stuff if possible. Be warned though that things might get pretty nasty at times. However we strongly believe that you will live through every hurdle and emerge victoriously in the end. Hope you will enjoy the ride as much as we do, gentle reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Scaling (by *de Gennes*)&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/deGennes.png&quot; class=&quot;lead&quot; data-width=&quot;800&quot; data-height=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The simple, elegant and powerful idea of &quot;scaling&quot; (See &lt;i&gt;footnote&lt;/i&gt;).&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-journey-in-a-nutshell&quot;&gt;The Journey in a Nutshell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our study of polymers and also membranes, we will be quite humble and take the simple approach of a working theoretical physicist. We will focus only on universal (or &lt;em&gt;global&lt;/em&gt;) properties of these macromolecular systems at large length scales. All microscopic details, which may be of utmost importance to a polymer chemist but not necessarily to a fellow physicist, will be ignored. As we are concerned with very long chains only, microscopics play a minor role. We will, hence, employ simple highly &lt;em&gt;coarse-grained&lt;/em&gt; models. In spite of their simplicity, you will see for yourself the beauty and efficacy of these models in making fairly accurate predictions for some of the equilibrium properties of these wonderful physical systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series will be divided in five parts in accordance to the corresponding five sections of the text. The first part will deal with the simplest model of a polymer, &lt;em&gt;viz.&lt;/em&gt; the “Gaussian chain”. The concept of &lt;em&gt;entropic elasticity&lt;/em&gt; will be quickly introduced; this is analogous to the Hooke’s law of a harmonic spring. In the second part we will talk about self-avoidance and its effects on the properties of a polymer in a good solvent. Then in the third part the statistics of a polymer will be related to that of the &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;-vector model and thus make contact with continuous (or 2nd order) phase transitions. Part 4 will introduce you to polymers in concentrated solutions. Finally Part 5 will give you a flavor of some aspects of the statistical mechanics of membranes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like in the case of polymers, our picture of membranes will be a really simple one. We will either talk about a 2D network or mesh of particles (the &lt;em&gt;tethered membrane&lt;/em&gt;) or consider freely floating particles on an elastic 2D surface (the &lt;em&gt;liquid membrane&lt;/em&gt;). So we won’t be interested in the microscopic details. This approach might anger and disappoint the biologists.  However, our crude coarse-grained models will be sufficient enough to describe and explain large scale properties, which is what we as physicists are really after. These models are beautiful and elegant and additionally provide a nice example of how &lt;em&gt;dimensionality&lt;/em&gt; plays an important role in statistical physics. Therefore, it is important to study them in the way we do, however idiosyncratic that may be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;books--bibles&quot;&gt;Books &amp;amp; Bibles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some classic texts on the subject for your ready reference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;de Gennes, &lt;a href=&quot;https://physicstoday.scitation.org/doi/10.1063/1.2914118&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scaling concepts in polymer physics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Doi &amp;amp; Edwards, &lt;em&gt;The Theory of Polymer Dynamics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rubinstein &amp;amp; Colby, &lt;em&gt;Polymer Physics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grosberg &amp;amp; Khoklov, &lt;em&gt;Statistical Physics of Macromolecules&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yamakawa, &lt;em&gt;Modern Theory of Polymer Solutions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--That's it! Until we meet again, *adios*. Stay tuned for [Part 1](/2020/05/25/fascinating-polymers-and-membranes-part-1.html) of the series.--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; The study of membranes is a relatively new field and came into the scene only in the 80s. Plischke &amp;amp; Bergersen seems to be the only textbook which talks about it. :notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time for a musical break. Enchanted by Strings . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;video&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ptk_1Dc2iPY&quot; title=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; style=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;          &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this we end the introductory episode. Move on to &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/05/25/enchanted-by-strings-part-1.html&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; of the series next.
Let the fun commence. :trident:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--*TO BE CONTINUED* . . .--&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The figure above depicts “various animals attempting to follow a scaling law.” P.G. de Gennes’s sketched this himself for his classic monograph. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">TL;DR: This series is an ode to a beautiful chapter on polymers and membranes in the classic text of Equilibrium Statistical Physics by Plischke &amp;amp; Bergersen. All the contents to be shared are copied. The author of this blog claims no originality whatsoever. Our aim is solely to guide you through the text and open your eyes to a whole new world, which we believe is often overlooked and misunderstood. If you are afraid of math and scary looking equations, then this post and the upcoming ones are not for you. The contents of the text is pretty elementary though, suitable for an ambitious upper undergraduate or a graduate (in Physics presumably).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LaTeX in Markdown</title><link href="https://doctorpsi.github.io/2020/05/18/latex-in-markdown.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LaTeX in Markdown" /><published>2020-05-18T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-18T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://doctorpsi.github.io/2020/05/18/latex-in-markdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://doctorpsi.github.io/2020/05/18/latex-in-markdown.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\LaTeX&lt;/script&gt; is an amazing language for typesetting beautiful looking documents. It’s especially  useful if you deal with a lot of math. Here’s an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\dot{v} = - \zeta v + \eta(t)&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started-with-markdown&quot;&gt;Getting started with Markdown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown is a nice tool to quickly write nicely formatted plaintext (without all the fuss).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get started!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s quite easy to format text in markdown: This is &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt;. And this is &lt;em&gt;italics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is a blockquote.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“You can write some quotes here.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now some grocery list. Comes in quite handy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apples&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bananas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guavas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also have bullets. Great Scott!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One bullet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two bullets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three bullets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typing another equation . . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\alpha+\beta+\gamma=0&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about some &lt;em&gt;inline&lt;/em&gt; math, like &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;F = m a&lt;/script&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or would you like something fancy? See &lt;a href=&quot;http://katex.org&quot;&gt;KaTeX&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\displaystyle \frac{1}{\Bigl(\sqrt{\phi \sqrt{5}}-\phi\Bigr) e^{\frac25 \pi}} = 1+\frac{e^{-2\pi}} {1+\frac{e^{-4\pi}} {1+\frac{e^{-6\pi}} {1+\frac{e^{-8\pi}} {1+\cdots} } } }&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: I’m using MathJax now with a Jekyll plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some &lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt; code. Indent text to get a codeblock:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;printf(&quot;%s\n&quot;,&quot;I'm a codeblock.&quot;);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: Markdown (on it’s own) doesn’t support syntax highlighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want nicely colored code, use “fenced” codeblocks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-c highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;%s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;I'm a codeblock.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// with syntax highlighting&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also do it the Jekyll way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot; data-lang=&quot;c&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;/* Some ritualistic code*/&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;#include &amp;lt;math.h&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;%s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;se&quot;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello world!&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;//=&amp;gt; prints 'Hello world!' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is some text, followed by a footnote &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TO BE UPDATED&lt;/em&gt; . . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(As I learn More)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Some &lt;em&gt;crazy&lt;/em&gt; footnote, As You Like It. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">is an amazing language for typesetting beautiful looking documents. It’s especially useful if you deal with a lot of math. Here’s an example:</summary></entry></feed>